Guide to the DeVane Lecture Series, Yale University, Audiorecordings
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
DeVane Lecture Series, Yale University, audiorecordings
1998-2001
RU 1069
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
(67 boxes)
The materials consist of audiorecordings of lectures and discussion sessions from Yale University's DeVane Lecture Series.
Yale University. President's Office
DeVane, William C. (William Clyde), 1898-1965
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-A (YRG 2-A), Records of the Yale president's office.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Association of Yale Alumni, 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
This materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Biographical / Historical
The DeVane lectures were established in 1969 in honor of William Clyde DeVane, dean of Yale College from 1939 to 1963. The series has traditionally covered a different topic each year, ranging from democracy to Yale's role in the 20th century. The lecture series is organized and financed by the President's Office and is open to the general public as well as to Yale students. Only Yale students though are permitted to attend the discussion sections, and the lecture series counts as a full Yale credit.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of audiorecordings of lectures and discussion sessions from Yale University's DeVane Lecture Series.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged chronologically.
Lectures and lecturing; Audiotapes; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University. President's Office
- DeVane Lecture Series audiorecordings, 1998-2001; Accession 2008-A-123
  - Nancy F. Cott, Stanley Woodward Professor of History and American Studies, 1998 Spring
    - Lecture, audiocassette (Box 1)
    - Q and A, 1998 January 21; audiocassette (Box 2)
    - Lecture, 1998 January 28; audiocassette (Box 3)
    - Q and A, 1998 January 28; audiocassette (Box 4)
    - Lecture, 1998 February 4; audiocassette (Box 5)
    - Q and A, 1998 February 4; audiocassette (Box 6)
    - Lecture, 1998 February 11; audiocassette (Box 7)
    - Q and A, 1998 February 11; audiocassette (Box 8)
    - Lecture, 1998 February 18; audiocassette (Box 9)
    - Q and A, 1998 February 18; audiocassette (Box 10)
    - Lecture, 1998 February 25; audiocassette (Box 11)
    - Q and A, 1998 February 25; audiocassette (Box 12)
    - Lecture, 1998 March 4; audiocassette (Box 13)
    - Q and A, 1998 March 4; audiocassette (Box 14)
    - Lecture, 1998 March 25; audiocassette (Box 15)
    - Lecture, 1998 March 31; audiocassette (Box 16)
    - Q and A, 1998 March 31; audiocassette (Box 17)
    - Lecture (part 1), 1998 April 8; audiocassette (Box 18)
    - Lecture (part 2), 1998 April 8; audiocassette (Box 19)
    - Q and A, 1998 April 8; audiocassette (Box 19)
    - Lecture, 1998 April 15; audiocassette (Box 20)
    - Q and A, 1998 April 15; audiocassette (Box 21)
    - Lecture, 1998 April 22; audiocassette (Box 22)
    - Q and A, 1998 April 22; audiocassette (Box 23)
  - Gaddis Smith, Professor of History,"Yale and the External World: the Shaping of the University in the 20th Century", 1998 Fall
    - 1998 Sep 7, audiocassette (Box 24)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 24U)
    - 1998 Sep 14 (unedited), audiocassette (Box 25)
    - 1998 Sep 14 (edited), audiocassette (Box 26)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 26U)
    - 1998 Sep 18, audiocassette (Box 27)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 27U)
    - 1998 Sep 21, audiocassette (Box 28)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 28U)
    - 1998 Sep 28, audiocassette (Box 29)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 29U)
    - 1998 Oct 5, audiocassette (Box 30)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 30U)
    - 1998 Oct 12, audiocassette (Box 31)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 31U)
    - 1998 Oct 20, audiocassette (Box 32)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 32U)
    - 1998 Oct 26, audiocassette (Box 33)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 33U)
    - 1998 Nov 2, audiocassette (Box 34)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 34U)
    - 1998 Nov 9, audiocassette (Box 35)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 35U)
    - 1998 Nov 16, audiocassette (Box 36)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 36U)
    - 1998 Nov 30, audiocassette (Box 37)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 37U)
    - 1998 Dec 7, audiocassette (Box 38)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 38U)
  - "Democratic Vistas"
    - Anthony Kronman, Dean of the Yale Law School, "The Democratic Soul,"audiocassette (87 minutes), 2001 January 9, 11 (Box 39)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        General
        See: RU 884, ACCN2003-A-118, Box 12U
    - David Bromwich, Bird White Housum Professor of English, "Abraham Lincoln and Walt Whitman as Representative Americans," audiocassette(62 minutes), 2001 January 16, 18 (Box 40)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 13U
    - Mahzarin Banaji, Reuben Post halleck Professor of Psychology, "Paradoxes of Mind and Society: The Bounded Nature of Cognition and the Unbounded Possibilities for American Democracy," audiocassette (45 minutes), 2001 January 23, 25 (Box 41)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 14
    - Ian Shapiro, William R. Kenan, Jr. Professor and Chairman, Political Science, "Democracy and Distribution," audiocassette (66 minutes), 2001 January 30, February 1 (Box 42)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 7
    - Richard C. Levin, President of Yale and Frederick William Beinecke Professor of Economics, "Democracy and the Market," audiocassette (69 minutes), 2001 February 6, 8 (Box 43)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 9
    - Michael Denning, Professor of American Studies and Chair of the Program in Ethnicity, Race and Migration, "Neither Capitalist nor American: The Democracy as Social Movement," audiocassette (59 minutes), 2001 February 13, 15 (Box 44)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 15U
    - Bruce Ackerman, Sterling Professor of Law and Political Science, "The Death of Citizenship?" audiocassette (66 minutes), 2001 (Box 45)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 8U
    - Joan A. Steitz, Sterling Professor of Molecular Biophysics and Biochemistry, "American Democracy and the Origins of the Biomedical Revolution," audiocassette (74 minutes), 2001 February 27, March 1 (Box 46)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 16U
    - David Gelernter, Professor of Computer Science, "Democracy and Computers -- Pitfalls, Possibilities," audiocassette (51 minutes), 2001 March 20, 22 (Box 47)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 17U
    - Richard Brodhead, Dean of Yale College and A.Bartlett Giamatti Professor of English and Professor of American Studies, "Democracy and Education," audiocassette (62 minutes), 2001 March 27, 29 (Box 48)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 18U
    - Nancy F. Cott, Sterling Professor of History, "Democracy and the Family," audiocassette (55 minutes), 2001 April 3, 5 (Box 49)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 19U
    - Stephen L. Carter, William Nelson Cromwell Professor of Law, "Can Religion Tolerate Democracy (and Vice Versa)?" audiocassette (68 minutes), 2001 April 10, 12 (Box 50)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 20U
    - John Lewis Gaddis, Robert A. Lovett Professor of Military and Naval History, "Democracy and Foreign Policy," audiocassette (61 minutes), 2001 April 17, 19 (Box 51)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 10U
    - James C. Scott, Eugene Meyer Professor of Political Science and Professor of Anthropology, "Meritocracy and Democracy: The Temptations of Mechanical, "Objective," and Impersonal Measures of Quality," audiocassette (69 minutes), 2001 April 24, 26 (Box 52)
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 21U
    - Richard Benson, Dean of the School of Art, Professor of Photography, "Pictures for the People: Visual Multiples and their Role as Supporting Tools for the Democratic Process" [not received], 2001 May 1, 3
      - Videotape (VHS)
        See: RU 884, ACCN 2003-A-118, Box 11
    - Brochure (Box 53)
  - Robert A.M. Stern, Dean School of Architecture, "Ideals Without Ideologies: Yale's Contribution to Modern Architecture", 2001 September 10 - December 10
    See: RU 880, ACCN 2002-A-151, Boxes 7-18